

Faisal Adam Yudithia

first.yudithia@gmail.com (+62) 821-4069-4429 linkedin.com/in/faisal-yudithia

SUMMARY

First and foremost, I love writing code. Ever since graduating data science bootcamp this year, I have been obsessed with the idea of using data to solve business problems. Currently working as a data management development specialist in the tobacco industry that responsible for developing the services for the data pipeline. Passionate about big data, business, and technology.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember | Surabaya, Indonesia

Graduated in Aug 2020

- Graduated with a very satisfactory predicate (GPA 3.03)
- Conducted thesis research about the analysis of biodiversity distribution of trees in urban areas using machine learning
- Served as chief executive of nature and social awareness club for 2017 to 2018 academic year
- · Participated in the event and organizational management skills training for institute students

SKILLS

- Analytical Thinking
- Creative Problem-Solving
- Spatial Analysis
- Data Analytics
- Data Visualization
- Machine Learning
- Database Management
- SQL
- Oracle

- Git
- Python
- Tableau

WORK EXPERIENCES

Data Management Development Specialist

PT Surya Madistrindo (Gudang Garam Group) | Jakarta, Indonesia

Feb 2022 - Present

- Develop reusable and reliable query to ensure data reliability, efficiency, and quality
- Design, develop, and maintain the services for the data pipeline
- Produce report and visualize strong quality data insights to drive business decisions

Drone Pilot & Data Processing Specialist

PT Sky Tech Indonesia (Avirtech Group) | Jakarta, Indonesia

Dec 2020 - Sep 2021

- Operated mapping drone to capture aerial images of client's plantation area
- Processed aerial imagery data and analyzed plantation conditions using GIS software, obtained >90% data pass rate
- Kickstarted the development of a relational database to streamline acquisition data collection using Microsoft Excel and VBA

GIS Analyst Intern

PT Pertamina EP (Pertamina Group) | Jakarta, Indonesia

Aug 2018 - Sep 2018

- Implemented innovations related to company asset management, achieved an excellent grade of the internship program
- Processed aerial imagery and LiDAR data using ArcGIS Pro
- Created statistics dashboard and 3D building models of its production facilities

ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCES

Chief Executive

Pencinta Lingkungan Hidup SIKLUS ITS | Surabaya, Indonesia

Aug 2017 - Dec 2018

- Led the organization and supervised four divisions, consisting of 25 individuals on the board
- Controlled member performance and monthly activity target, obtained >75% accumulated event target achieved
- Represented organization as a speaker in the plastic-free campaign in front of society, impacted 100+ people around

CERTIFICATIONS

- Rakamin Academy Certified in the Data Science Machine Learning Bootcamp with Excellent Grade
- Programming Hub Certified in the SQL Programming Course
- Programming Hub Certified in the Programming Fundamentals Course
- ITS EFL Test Certified in the Test of English as a Foreign Language with a Score of 480